claim that the U.S has a quote
long-standing history of exclusively
supporting Democratic governmental
transition in light of recent CIA
activity to counter Syrian president
Assad including the reported training
and arming of rebels in Jordan and
elsewhere and ngos backing Euro maiden
and anti-russian groups in Ukraine why
is the state department making these
kinds of claims
I think the state Department's claims
are patently absurd first of all let's
look just at the Middle East
um Bahrain is an absolute monarchy it's
a dictatorship there has been a
democratic movement there for more than
20 years the state department has never
supported it indeed the state department
hasn't even really addressed the issue
of human rights violations in Bahrain
Saudi Arabia is worse there's actually a
law in this com in this country called
the Specter amendment that says that the
United States may not sell arms to a
country that does not in Institute
Democratic reforms Saudi Arabia is one
of our leading purchasers of military
equipment let's look at Palestine Hamas
won a democratic election
we've done nothing to recognize Hamas as
the Democratic representative of the
Palestinian people or even just the
gazan people
Egypt did have a democratic election
right and uh the Muslim Brotherhood won
well as soon as the Muslim Brotherhood
turned out to be somebody we didn't want
to do business with we supported a
military coup and an ensuing military
dictatorship we can go back farther in
history we can talk about Iran we can
talk about Guatemala in the 50s we can
talk about the Dominican Republic in the
60s we can talk about Greece a NATO
country and we supported the overthrow
of the democratically elected government
of Greece in 1967 and then did nothing
to encourage democracy until the Greek
people overthrew their own dictatorship
in 1974. so for the state department
spokesman to say something like this
either she thinks the American people
are stupid or she's horribly misinformed
well as for Egypt I suppose my
understanding was that a vote for the
Muslim Brotherhood in that case was
really a vote by the Egyptians to
discontinue elections after that I mean
given their stated views of what they
were going to do but the Muslim
Brotherhood never said that it was one
vote one man one vote one time they
never said that
um there were no Democratic institutions
in Egypt in the first place
I think in part because we've supported
the the Mubarak and and before him the
uh the uh Sadat government you know for
so many decades but for us to just say
well the Muslim Brotherhood they're
really not Democratic so we should
probably support their overthrow I think
it's disingenuous
so following the killing of Osama bin
Laden CIA director Panetta encouraged
Obama to release death photos of the
al-Qaeda leader due to concerns that a
lack of transparency would lead to
skepticism about the event having taken
place at all which that skepticism came
to fruition among some people and
weighing that concern against the
definitely inflammatory nature of the
photographs what do you make of the
president's decision not to release the
photos
uh I thought it showed a lack of
transparency I would have released the
photos for the same reasons that Panetta
said that they should be released I
think we should have released them at
the time even if they angry people or
they seemed like they were right well I
mean Al Qaeda is going to be angry
whether there are photos or not they're
going to attack us whether they're
photos or not and I think that it would
have gone it would have gone a release
of the photos would have gone a long way
to uh to sort of uh
put to rest some of the concerns that we
had made the whole thing up would you
have liked to have seen civilian trials
in Manhattan or absolutely Northern
Virginia court for the absolutely
we of course we have a historic
precedent for for civilian trials in
this country I don't know why all of a
sudden we're so afraid of Al Qaeda that
we have to try them in a military Court
in Guantanamo what about the blind
Sheikh he was tried in a civilian Court
what about uh the the First World Trade
Center bombers they were tried in in a
civilian Court we didn't have any
problems and as far as congressmen not
wanting uh prisoners like like senior Al
Qaeda senior Al Qaeda leaders in their
in their districts and prisons in their
districts well we already have super max
prisons in their districts what's the
difference whether we have an Al-Qaeda
person in there or not it doesn't make
any sense to me
yeah they held McVeigh for a while there
sure they did until they sure they did
that's right
so the NSA was tracking mon in the lead
up to 9 11 the NSA was tracking
monitoring and recording 911 hijackers
phone calls which of which they
apparently still have recordings uh in
order to qualm those who would doubt the
911 Commission report and holder in part
do you think the NSA should be obligated
to release original similar Source
materials like that
I don't know uh to be honest with you
I'd like to see the source material I
don't I don't really care if I you know
for me as a private citizen to hear the
recordings but I'd certainly like to see
transcripts even more than that I'd like
to see congress's full and unredacted
report on the 911 attacks I think that's
where we would really get the truth
Senator Bob Graham came out the other
day and said he was talking about these
28 redacted Pages pointing to official
Saudi involvement in 9 11. I'd love to
see what that says
yeah what do you think I was about to
ask about that why don't you think
Graham is taking heat for now more
brazenly alluding to the 28 pages of the
911 Commission report they were redacted
when when will be too much you know it
seems like he's slowly slowly he's
walking right up to the edge right now I
agree with you you know and and one
interesting thing about Bob Graham
um and this is why I think we should
take this very seriously is Bob Graham
is a serious guy Bob Graham was a was a
very important Senator he was a member
of the uh of the Senate select committee
on intelligence highly respected on both
sides of the aisle if Bob Graham says
that he believes there was official
Saudi involvement I'm going to believe
Bob Grant and I think really the
American people are owed an explanation
do you think it was uh official Saudi
involvement or just just Saudi Elite
sewer I personally don't believe it was
official Saudi involvement but I think
that there were Saudi Elites including
probably members of the Saudi royal
family who were supportive of Al Qaeda
right I'd like to see the source
material right of course
so you would support its release and of
course uh I think almost a dozen members
of Congress or co-sponsors of a build
and get that material out there do you
think do you think it'll get leaked this
is total total speculation but what sort
of timeline and how long do you think
it'll be till we see it I think the
Obama Administration has so frightened
people about leaks that unless they're
they're pro-administration or somehow
further the government's position on
issues I think they probably won't be
leaked yeah it seems like they're mostly
you know Libertarians like Amash or
farther left you know it seems like
that's most of the that's right
characters who want it out there what's
the what's the pressure this is this
about oil you know is that what these 28
pages are about what's the difference is
it about oil is it about this this long
time relationship we've we've had with
the Saudi royal family uh is it about
offending people who have a major stake
in our economy
right probably right
so when you foresaw that Graham question
here's a good one so in a recent
interview with John Oliver Edward
Snowden addressed a redaction error by
the New York Times
which it snowed himself called a mistake
the mistake revealed NSA cognizant
cognizance of a mobile instant messaging
program in use several years ago by Al
Qaeda in Iraq how can aspiring
whistleblowers like Snowden way
especially a single whistleblower weigh
ethically the potential for
inadvertently helping terrorists or
enemies of the nation against the ideal
of Defending civil liberties oh that's a
great question I think that's a very
important question
um and I'm going to compare it to my own
situation
what I should have done is what I think
future whistleblowers should do I should
have consulted an attorney who
specializes in whistleblower cases
before going public and I think that any
future potential whistleblower should
also consult
an attorney who has familiarity with
these issues to go over perhaps what
he's thinking about exposing because
accidents like this happen and in some
cases well we can certainly lose the
intelligence like what as Snowden was
talking about but in some cases people
can lose their lives because of
inadvertent
exposure do you think snowden's
ultimately responsible for the release
of that information even though the New
York Times did it
well sure he's ultimately responsible
and and I will say let me say two things
about it Snowden first of all I think he
did a great national service I think he
exposed evidence of of abuse and
illegality uh against American citizens
on the part of NSA uh I think we owe him
a debt of gratitude with that said
I wouldn't have leaked everything that
Snowden leaked there are some things
that I think should have been kept
secret this being one thing another
being the fact that NSA was intercepting
the communications of foreign leaders
that's exactly what NSA is supposed to
be doing that's what we want NSA to do
we don't want NSA to spy on American
citizens I believe that's illegal it's
certainly a violation of nsa's own
Charter but I want them to focus
overseas
and but soon seems to be concerned about
spying on foreigners he he tells that he
admitted in the John Oliver interview
that no one cares about it but he is
outraged by it yeah he shouldn't be well
I mean I shouldn't talk for it's known
I'm not I I like I say I want NSA to be
spying on foreign Nationals I know
you're not talking for Snowden yeah yeah
what I don't think you're his lawyer so
by the way just just a legal Point uh
you would certainly know this you're a
lawyer but you if someone wants to be a
whistleblower can they consult an
attorney with specialization in in IG
issues and whistleblowing without having
broken their Oaths without having
violated their non-disclosure agreements
yes you can certainly talk around issues
you can do it several different ways you
can go to the Inspector General of your
agency or I think more appropriately you
can go to the oversight committee that's
the house permanent select committee on
intelligence or the Senate select
committee on intelligence uh and you can
talk to them it's their job to oversee
the agencies that make up the
intelligence community so they're fully
cleared they're read into all the
compartments you can speak freely with
with members of Congress and and their
cleared staffs there are also several
whistleblower
um attorneys active in Washington
whistleblower organizations active in
Washington that are that are led by
attorneys and while they're not cleared
necessarily for the information you can
certainly talk around the information
and address the issue of whistleblowing
versus the specific classified